1#EmailAddressAlreadyExists#This email adress already exists in our system.  Please try to log-in or request new password.
2#NotValidEmailAddress#This is not a valid email address
3#PasswordPolicyCheck#Please enter a password that is 6 characters or more.
4#PasswordDoesNotMatch#Passwords don't match, please re-enter
5#StoreAlreadyExistsInDb#This store already added. If you have another store please add it now.
6#StoreAdded#Congratulations. Your store was added successfully.
7#AccountAlreadyExixtsInDb#This PayPal account already exists in our system under a different user.
9#PayPalAddedByYou#You've already added this PayPal account
10#StoreAddedByYou#You've already added this store. If you have another store please add it now.
11#QuickSignUpTopNotification#You are now opening a FREE, SECURE, and PERSONAL account and minutes away from receiving monies.
13#QuickSignUpSecurityStatement#You are under no obligation, there is no cost to this service.  EZBOB uses state of the art security : all your data is kept secure!!!
15#QuickSignUpNeedHelp#Need Help?  Try live chat, email, or call ####
16#QuickSignUpCommonQuestions#<ul><li>What is EZBOB?</li><li>How long is the Process?</li><li>When will I receive my money?</li></ul>
17#QuickSignUpNotifications#As part of the appilcation process, you are opening your own, private, EZBOB account.   The entire applicatin process takes no more than 10 minutes to complete. 
19#StoreInfoSecurityStatement#Security and Privacy are  paramount at EZBOB. Your information is not shared with any 3rd party.
20#StoreInfoCommonQuestions#<ul><li>Does EZBOB have access to my store?</li><li>Benefits of adding a store?</li><li>What information does EZBOB collect?</li></ul>
21#AmazonTutorial#We have created a simple visual tutorial to guide you through the process.
22#AmazonCommonQuestions#If I add another store how much more money can I get?  Does EZBOB have access to my store?
24#AmazonSecurityStatement#EZBOB never sees your store passwords.  We have read only access to your details.
25#StoreNotification#EZBOB does not have access to your passwords and cannot alter your store data in anyway.  EZBOB analyzes our online store data in order to make you a financing offer.
26#EbayTutorial#We have created a simple visual tutorial to guide you through the process.
28#PaymentAccountAdded#Congratulations. Your payment account was addded successfully.
29#StoreInfoTopNotification#EZBOB finances based on your online business.  Add your best store first.
31#StoreInfoAddMore#Add more stores get more money!
32#NoPayPalOrBankAccount#Now we need your payment details so we can send you money!
35#NoBankAccount#We need your Bank Account details so we can send you money!
36#AccountsAdded#The registration process is almost completed.
37#NoPayPalAccount#Since you are an Ebay seller we require your PayPal details.
38#PayPalTopNotification#Since you are an ebay seller, you must fill out your PayPal details.
39#PayPalTutorial#We have created a simple visual tutorial to guide you through the process.
40#PayPalQuestions#What happens if I don't have / fill out my PayPal details?  What does EZBOB do with my PayPal account details?  Do I get more money if I add my Paypal
